<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://azu.github.io/github-search-rss/github-roadmap.rss</id>
    <title>github/roadmap Issues</title>
    <updated>2025-01-27T11:01:16.333Z</updated>
    <generator>github-search-rss</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://azu.github.io/github-search-rss/github-roadmap.rss"/>
    <subtitle>github/roadmap Issues on GitHub</subtitle>
    <rights>github-search-rss</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows ARM hosted runners for OSS [Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1098</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1098"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T19:06:08.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Following on the release of Linux arm64 hosted runners, the GitHub-hosted runner portfolio is expanding to include arm64 hosted runners for free in public repositories. These runners will be fully managed by GitHub with a base image containing a foundational set of tools. These runners offer a power efficient compute layer which can increase price to performance ratios, allowing users to optimize compute costs.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">You can use arm64 runners to refactor your applications to take advantage of the price performance benefits of ARM architecture. You can now run their workloads on Arm-based hardware hosted by GitHub to build and deploy your release assets anywhere Arm’s architecture is used. These new runners provide power, performance &amp; sustainability improvements for all your Actions jobs.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T19:04:07.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share Copilot Chat Conversations [Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1097</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1097"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:54:42.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">The goal of this feature is to enhance collaboration and knowledge sharing among users by allowing them to easily share insightful Copilot conversations. By enabling the sharing of Copilot conversations, users can communicate their ideas, decisions, or findings effectively without compromising privacy. This feature aims to increase engagement with Copilot, foster collaborative exploration, and support various use cases for sharing data, ultimately driving adoption and growth.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">We are implementing this feature to enhance user engagement and collaboration within the Copilot ecosystem. By allowing users to share their Copilot conversations, we aim to:</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Increase the visibility and utility of Copilot by enabling users to share their productive interactions.</li>
<li>Foster a collaborative environment where users can learn from each other’s experiences and insights.</li>
<li>Drive user adoption and growth by leveraging the viral potential of shared conversations, which can attract new users to GitHub.</li>
<li>Gather valuable feedback and data on how users interact with shared content, which will inform future iterations and improvements of the feature.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:53:37.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enable Cron Expression Support for Dependabot Scheduling [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1096</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1096"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:52:07.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Today, Dependabot’s <code class="notranslate">schedule.interval</code> supports only predefined intervals: daily, weekly, and monthly. Users need a more flexible way to schedule custom Dependabot update frequencies.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Introducing support for cron expressions in <code class="notranslate">schedule.interval</code> in the <code class="notranslate">dependabot.yml</code> file will provide a more generic and robust solution, enabling users to define custom schedules that meet their specific needs.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:51:08.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Private Registry Org-Level Configuration for Java & C# for CodeQL [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1095</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1095"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:48:07.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">A new organization-level configuration option for adding secrets to access private registries will improve coverage for buildless CodeQL scans for Java and C#. Developers will have more confidence in the accuracy of the scans, and false negatives will be further reduced. Organization administrators will be able to easily add these credentials for use across all their repositories at once, reducing time spent on configuration and setup for CodeQL.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Coverage and confidence of CodeQL scans will increase with this feature, leading to even better security outcomes and increased peace-of-mind for security managers, with minimal overhead for configuration and management.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:47:50.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EPSS Scores for Dependabot Alerts [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1094</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1094"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:44:25.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">EPSS (Exploit Prediction Scoring System) is a data-driven framework that estimates the likelihood of a software vulnerability being exploited in the wild. It helps organizations prioritize patching efforts based on real-world risk.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With EPSS scores in Dependabot alerts, customers can expect a new way to prioritize their Dependabot updates based on likelihood of exploitation via EPSS score.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:44:10.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code scanning: Status information at the organization level [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1093</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1093"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:41:38.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Security overview will include code scanning status information for all repositories within the organization.</p>
<p dir="auto">Users will see a color coded identification of "green," "yellow," or "red" next to each repository in the organization. These indicators represent the status of the code scanning tool's setup and performance. Customers can access the repository to enhance the tool's performance.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">The feature will streamline code scanning setup and adoption. When users enable code scanning across an organization at scale, they can identify repositories where a code scanning tool is underperforming or malfunctioning and take corrective measures.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:40:31.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enterprise Governance: Custom repo properties for enterprise [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1092</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1092"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:38:21.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Enterprise repository properties allows for the management of custom repository properties across your entire enterprise, allowing teams to apply consistent metadata across all of their repos.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With enterprise repository properties, enterprises have a way to share consistent properties across all of their organization without having to manually synchronize properties and deal with duplication. This gives administrators a common way to describe their repositories, empowering consistent application of rules and search parameters.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:38:02.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enterprise Governance: Repository policy rules]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1090</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1090"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:34:55.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Enterprise repository policies, allows enterprise and organizations administrators to control key repository lifecycle events. This allows for targeting of policy to manage repository creations, deletions, transfers, visibility changes and names either for all repositories or more granularly with custom property targeting.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">By using enterprise repository policies enterprises and organizations can enforce guardrails to ensure new repos can be created meeting their organizational standards and ensure existing repositories are prevented from making accidental changes. This ensures your private repositories are not made accidentally public or deleted, keeping your repositories more secure.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:34:38.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copilot Free in GitHub Mobile]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1089</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1089"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:30:56.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Developers can now interact with Copilot for free in GitHub Mobile.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With this update, developers can start using Copilot Chat in Mobile right away and access to 2,000 code completions and 50 chat messages per month. When the quota is hit, users can purchase a Copilot Pro subscription directly in the iOS version of GitHub Mobile, or in the Google Play Store for the Android version of GitHub Mobile.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:30:44.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Custom Fields across Projects [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1088</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1088"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:27:47.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">We want to make it easier to share and sync item information across projects. This will make it easier to keep items and their metadata up to date and remove the need for manual updates and edits.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">By helping keep information up-to-date across multiple projects, teams can rely on a single source of truth where critical details remain consistent, easy to find, and free from manual effort.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:27:26.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nested sub-issues in projects [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1087</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1087"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:24:51.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">We’re introducing the ability to visualize nested sub-issues directly within Projects. This enhancement allows you to explore full hierarchies, making it easier to manage work across multiple epics and initiatives.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">We have heard your feedback that viewing nested sub-issues within Projects is important for advanced planning and tracking purposes. We want to enable your teams to power up your workflows, by making it easier for you to understand the full scope of you work across your epics and initiatives.</p>
<p dir="auto"><a target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer" href="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/dabeed96-9e0a-4060-b051-452aa2e7ab27"><img src="https://github.com/user-attachments/assets/dabeed96-9e0a-4060-b051-452aa2e7ab27" alt="Image" style="max-width: 100%;"></a></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:24:32.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Cross-repository milestones [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1086</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1086"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:08:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Milestones are a key component of planning and tracking work on GitHub, allowing you to organise issues in a time-based group. Today milestones only work against the repository they are created in, which limits how useful they can be in projects which span across multiple repositories.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With this release, milestones can now include issues from multiple repositories, making them much more useful for grouping and tracking issues—for example, when communicating a release, marking a point in time, or targeting a specific goal.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:08:01.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeQL can scan C/C++ without a working build [Public Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1085</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1085"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:04:32.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">C/C++ project are notorious for being tricky to analyse with CodeQL. The main reason is because the tool requires a successful build in order to extract information that is needed for a scan. We are now planning to take an approach similar to Java / C# where you can analyse C/C++ code without relying on 3rd party tools to run a full build. Instead, you can use CodeQL to extract as much of the information as possible, add tolerance to errors, and continue with scans even if not all the code is extracted.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With the ability to scan C/C++ without working builds, users will be able to quickly scale CodeQL across their C/C++ repositories. As no build is required, CodeQL and default setup will roll out across your organizations without additional input needed.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:03:51.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[CodeQL supports C# Blazor [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1084</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1084"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T17:58:16.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">CodeQL can scan the majority of C# applications, but it currently does not support Blazor, a popular framework. Adding support to scan Blazor will enable CodeQL to completely cover applications that use the Blazor framework.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Users using the Blazor Framework to build their applications will start seeing files related to the parts of the application built in Blazor, included in the list of files scanned by CodeQL. This means that they will potentially see new CodeQL alerts related to parts of the application built in Blazor.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T17:57:59.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Models (Registry/Catalog/Playground) [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1083</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1083"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T17:53:48.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Proposition</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Models provides developers with seamless access to a variety of top-tier AI models through an intuitive playground, API, and additional tools. This feature enhances the developer experience by enabling side-by-side model comparisons, saving and sharing model presets, and supporting multimodal inputs. Additionally, GitHub Models streamlines the deployment process with Azure production keys, making it easier for developers to transition from development to production. With the ability to use models directly from the command line, within GitHub Copilot, and in VS Code through the Azure AI Toolkit, GitHub Models offers a versatile and powerful suite of tools for AI development.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Customer Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">By utilizing GitHub Models, developers can expect to significantly improve their productivity and efficiency in AI development. The side-by-side comparison feature allows for quick and effective model evaluation, while the model presets save time and effort in setting up and sharing configurations. The streamlined deployment process reduces the time to market for AI applications. Additionally, the integration with various tools and platforms ensures that developers can access and utilize AI models in their preferred environments, leading to a more cohesive and efficient development workflow. Ultimately, GitHub Models empowers developers to innovate faster and more effectively with advanced AI capabilities.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T17:53:30.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Mobile - Create pull request from existing branches [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1080</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1080"/>
        <updated>2024-12-13T21:14:43.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Developers can now create a pull request directly from an existing branch on Mobile, making the workflow smoother between mobile and desktop to enhance productivity.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Users can review edited files and open a pull request from an existing branch anytime, anywhere. Simply tap the <code class="notranslate">+</code> button on the repository or pull request view, select a branch, review the code and create a pull request if everything looks good. You can then continue testing or making adjustments on the desktop, making the development process more flexible and efficient.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2024-12-13T21:14:27.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copilot Chat users can use Gemini Pro [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1079</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1079"/>
        <updated>2024-12-13T21:12:48.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Proposition</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Copilot now supports a multi-model approach, allowing developers to choose from industry-leading models, including Google's Gemini Pro. This flexibility enables developers to select the most suitable model for specific tasks, enhancing their coding experience in Visual Studio Code and on github.com/copilot. By integrating multiple models, GitHub Copilot empowers developers to leverage the strengths of various AI models, optimizing code generation, refactoring, and overall development efficiency.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Customer Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With the introduction of multi-model support in GitHub Copilot, developers can expect improved accuracy and efficiency in their coding workflows. The ability to toggle between different models ensures that developers can utilize the best-suited AI for their specific needs, leading to higher quality code and faster development cycles. This feature provides developers with greater control and customization, ultimately enhancing productivity and innovation in their projects.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2024-12-13T21:12:35.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copilot Chat users can use Gemini Pro [Public Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1078</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1078"/>
        <updated>2024-12-13T21:11:15.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Proposition</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Copilot now supports a multi-model approach, allowing developers to choose from industry-leading models, including Google's Gemini Pro. This flexibility enables developers to select the most suitable model for specific tasks, enhancing their coding experience in Visual Studio Code and on github.com/copilot. By integrating multiple models, GitHub Copilot empowers developers to leverage the strengths of various AI models, optimizing code generation, refactoring, and overall development efficiency.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Customer Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With the introduction of multi-model support in GitHub Copilot, developers can expect improved accuracy and efficiency in their coding workflows. The ability to toggle between different models ensures that developers can utilize the best-suited AI for their specific needs, leading to higher quality code and faster development cycles. This feature provides developers with greater control and customization, ultimately enhancing productivity and innovation in their projects.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2024-12-13T21:10:01.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copilot Chat users can use Claude Sonnet 3.5 [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1077</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1077"/>
        <updated>2024-12-13T21:08:41.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Proposition</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Copilot now offers multi-model support, allowing developers to choose from industry-leading models, including Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet, to power their coding assistance. This flexibility enables developers to select the most suitable model for their specific use case, ensuring optimal performance and efficiency. By integrating multiple models into familiar workflows in Visual Studio Code and on github.com/copilot, GitHub is enhancing the developer experience and providing tailored AI-powered solutions.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Customer Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">By leveraging GitHub Copilot's multi-model support, developers can expect increased productivity and improved code quality by selecting the best model for each task. This feature empowers developers to handle diverse programming challenges more effectively, resulting in faster development cycles and more robust software solutions. Additionally, the seamless integration of Anthropic’s Claude 3.5 Sonnet ensures that developers have access to advanced AI capabilities, enhancing their ability to tackle complex coding problems from concept to deployment.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2024-12-13T21:08:26.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependencies on Issues]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1076</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1076"/>
        <updated>2024-12-13T21:07:05.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">We are providing users with the ability to track dependencies across issues. You will be able to set, manage, and view dependencies in issues.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">We have heard your feedback that dependencies are important for advanced planning and tracking purposes. We want to enable your teams to power up your workflows.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2024-12-13T21:05:17.000Z</published>
    </entry>
</feed>