<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://azu.github.io/github-search-rss/github-roadmap.rss</id>
    <title>github/roadmap Issues</title>
    <updated>2025-02-26T08:01:32.348Z</updated>
    <generator>github-search-rss</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://azu.github.io/github-search-rss/github-roadmap.rss"/>
    <subtitle>github/roadmap Issues on GitHub</subtitle>
    <rights>github-search-rss</rights>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Chat for Eclipse [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1111</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1111"/>
        <updated>2025-02-21T21:47:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Copilot for Eclipse Chat introduces AI-powered conversational assistance directly within the Eclipse IDE. This feature allows developers to ask coding-related questions, receive explanations, and get real-time support while writing code. By providing instant AI-driven guidance, Copilot for Eclipse Chat helps developers resolve issues faster, understand complex coding concepts, and stay in the flow without leaving their development environment. This interactive AI assistant enhances problem-solving and reduces dependencies on external searches.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With GitHub Copilot for Eclipse Chat, developers will experience faster issue resolution and improved understanding of their codebase. The conversational AI assistant empowers teams to code with greater confidence, reducing frustration and increasing efficiency. As developers receive real-time support without context-switching, productivity and software quality improve, leading to a more efficient and enjoyable development experience.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-21T21:47:02.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Code Completion for Eclipse [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1110</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1110"/>
        <updated>2025-02-21T21:44:46.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Copilot for Eclipse Code Completion leverages AI to provide intelligent, real-time code suggestions, significantly enhancing developer productivity. By understanding context and predicting the next lines of code, it helps developers write code faster and with fewer errors. This seamless integration into the Eclipse IDE reduces the need for constant reference checks and allows developers to stay focused on their tasks. With Copilot’s AI-driven completions, developers can accelerate their coding workflows and minimize the time spent on repetitive coding patterns.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With GitHub Copilot for Eclipse Code Completion, developers will experience a more streamlined coding process, reducing time spent on manual code writing and debugging. The AI-powered suggestions improve code accuracy and efficiency, leading to higher-quality software output. Teams can expect to see a boost in development speed and overall productivity, making Eclipse an even more powerful environment for modern software development.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-21T21:44:32.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Copilot Chat for Xcode [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1109</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1109"/>
        <updated>2025-02-21T21:42:47.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">GitHub Copilot for Xcode Chat brings AI-powered conversational coding assistance to Apple developers, enabling seamless integration into the Xcode IDE. With the ability to answer queries, provide code explanations, and suggest improvements in real-time, this feature transforms the development experience for iOS and macOS applications. By leveraging AI-driven insights, developers can quickly resolve coding challenges and optimize their workflows, ultimately accelerating application development.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With GitHub Copilot for Xcode Chat, Apple developers can expect more efficient coding sessions, faster debugging, and enhanced problem-solving capabilities. The AI assistant reduces the need for external research, keeping developers focused within Xcode. This leads to higher developer satisfaction, improved code quality, and shorter development cycles, making it an invaluable tool for iOS and macOS development teams.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-21T21:42:32.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Support Multi-Models Selection in Copilot Chat on GitHub Mobile [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1108</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1108"/>
        <updated>2025-02-20T20:55:06.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">We are bringing multi-model choice to GitHub Mobile to accelerate your workflow, whether you’re tackling coding questions, brainstorming ideas, or working on the go.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With this update, users would be able to select different models from the Copilot Chat UI on GitHub Mobile to get the best results based on specific use case.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:54:47.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copilot Free in GitHub CLI [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1107</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1107"/>
        <updated>2025-02-20T20:52:29.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Developers can now use the <code class="notranslate">gh-copilot</code> extension to interact with Copilot in the GitHub CLI on the Copilot Free tier.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With this update, developers can start using the <code class="notranslate">gh-copilot</code> extension for the GitHub CLI, using their 50 chat messages per month to get suggestions for and explanations of <code class="notranslate">gh</code>, <code class="notranslate">git</code>, and other terminal commands from Copilot. When the quota is hit, users can head to GitHub.com to purchase a Copilot Pro subscription.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:51:18.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Copilot Search on GitHub Docs [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1106</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1106"/>
        <updated>2025-02-21T17:32:09.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">The new Copilot Search on <a href="http://docs.github.com/">docs.github.com</a> transforms how teams interact with GitHub documentation. Copilot Search compiles comprehensive, actionable responses with links to related documentation, helping teams quickly resolve issues, discover tools, and improve their productivity with fewer interruptions.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Teams can expect faster issue resolution through direct answers. With less time spent searching and troubleshooting, teams will enhance productivity and reduce dependency on support.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:45:46.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependabot supports configuration of a minimum package age before creating a PR [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1105</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1105"/>
        <updated>2025-02-20T20:43:57.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">This feature allows Dependabot users to optionally configure a delay for opening a Dependabot PR for a newly updated dependency until a certain amount of time has passed.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">The cooldown feature helps teams improve security and reduce noise from frequent dependency updates by delaying Dependabot PRs for a configurable period, allowing time for patch releases and stabilizing updates without disrupting project workflows.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:43:41.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Audit history for Projects [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1104</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1104"/>
        <updated>2025-02-20T20:42:05.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">We are providing users with the ability to view and understand changes to a project and its items over time with an audit history log. This will allow them to see what changes were made, who made the changes, and when they were changed, allowing them to understand (and if needed, reverse action on) activity such as when an item was moved from <code class="notranslate">Low priority</code> to <code class="notranslate">High priority</code>.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">An audit history log would give more visibility into how a project and its items change over time, allowing users to track specific changes, understand how project items progress in a project with its custom fields, and reverse an action if it was unintended.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:41:46.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[GitHub Actions: Immutable Actions Publishing [Public Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1103</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1103"/>
        <updated>2025-02-20T20:41:40.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">We are building a new way to publish and consume actions that will improve the security of the CI/CD supply chain. Building on top of the OCI distribution specification, actions can now be pushed to GitHub Packages as immutable image versions with familiar semantic versions. The immutable packages and semantic versions bring greater predictability and security to users' workflows.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Users consuming actions will be able to reference an immutable package of an action by version, providing better security in their CI/CD supply chain. Over time we will build additional functionality like signing, build attestation, malware scanning, etc. to further improve the security of the supply chain and allow organizations to apply more specific policies. Developers creating Actions will have a fully automated workflow for publishing their actions that follows a natural build, package, and publish model with standard package versioning.</p>
<p dir="auto">Actions publishers will use a new packaging action and workflow to take their existing actions code and publish it to GitHub Packages. Users consuming actions by version tags will automatically start getting the packaged version of the action after it is published. Those referencing by commit SHA or git branch reference will simply need to switch to an appropriate version.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:39:02.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Improved Pull Request Files Changed Page [Public Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1102</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1102"/>
        <updated>2025-02-20T20:37:41.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">The Pull Request Files Changed page is being improved to provide more context at a glance, reduce distractions with improved filtering options, provide easier acccess to comments, support larger and more complex pull requests, and make the experience more accessible to everyone.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">These changes will improve the code review experience, while still remaining familiar to existing users. These improvements will make it easier to review changes (especially larger ones), stay on top of conversations, focus on the most relevant changes to you, all of which will help reduce review time, improve code quality, and improve velocity.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-02-20T20:36:54.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependabot version updates support `bun` package manager - [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1101</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1101"/>
        <updated>2025-02-13T23:23:10.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto"><code class="notranslate">Bun</code> is an all-in-one JavaScript runtime &amp; toolkit designed for speed, complete with a bundler, <a href="https://bun.sh/docs/cli/test" rel="nofollow">test runner</a>, and Node.js-compatible <a href="https://bun.sh/package-manager" rel="nofollow">package manager</a>. Today, customers cannot use the <code class="notranslate">bun</code> package manager with Dependabot. It's the most upvoted customer <a href="https://github.com/dependabot/dependabot-core/issues/6528" data-hovercard-type="issue" data-hovercard-url="/dependabot/dependabot-core/issues/6528/hovercard">request</a> in <code class="notranslate">dependabot-core</code>.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">This enables customers who use <code class="notranslate">bun</code> to get version updates from Dependabot.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-28T20:08:44.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependabot version updates support `uv` package manager - [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1100</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1100"/>
        <updated>2025-01-28T20:06:18.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Today, customers cannot use the <code class="notranslate">uv</code> package manager with Dependabot. It's one of the the most upvoted customer <a href="https://github.com/dependabot/dependabot-core/issues/10478" data-hovercard-type="issue" data-hovercard-url="/dependabot/dependabot-core/issues/10478/hovercard">requests</a> in <code class="notranslate">dependabot-core</code>.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">This enables customers who use <code class="notranslate">uv</code> to get version updates from Dependabot.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-28T20:06:02.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dependabot version updates support `docker-compose` package manager - [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1099</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1099"/>
        <updated>2025-01-28T20:02:17.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Docker Compose allows you to define your application's containers as code inside a YAML file you can commit to your source repository. It's one of the most upvoted customer request in dependabot-core. This issue adds Dependabot support for the docker-compose ecosystem.</p>
<p dir="auto">Today, customers cannot use the <code class="notranslate">docker-compose</code> package manager with Dependabot. It's one of the the most upvoted customer <a href="https://github.com/dependabot/dependabot-core/issues/390" data-hovercard-type="issue" data-hovercard-url="/dependabot/dependabot-core/issues/390/hovercard">requests</a> in <code class="notranslate">dependabot-core</code>.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">This enables customers who use <code class="notranslate">docker-compose</code> to get version updates from Dependabot.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-28T20:02:01.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Windows ARM hosted runners for OSS [Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1098</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1098"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T19:06:08.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Following on the release of Linux arm64 hosted runners, the GitHub-hosted runner portfolio is expanding to include arm64 hosted runners for free in public repositories. These runners will be fully managed by GitHub with a base image containing a foundational set of tools. These runners offer a power efficient compute layer which can increase price to performance ratios, allowing users to optimize compute costs.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">You can use arm64 runners to refactor your applications to take advantage of the price performance benefits of ARM architecture. You can now run their workloads on Arm-based hardware hosted by GitHub to build and deploy your release assets anywhere Arm’s architecture is used. These new runners provide power, performance &amp; sustainability improvements for all your Actions jobs.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T19:04:07.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Share Copilot Chat Conversations [Preview]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1097</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1097"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:54:42.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">The goal of this feature is to enhance collaboration and knowledge sharing among users by allowing them to easily share insightful Copilot conversations. By enabling the sharing of Copilot conversations, users can communicate their ideas, decisions, or findings effectively without compromising privacy. This feature aims to increase engagement with Copilot, foster collaborative exploration, and support various use cases for sharing data, ultimately driving adoption and growth.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">We are implementing this feature to enhance user engagement and collaboration within the Copilot ecosystem. By allowing users to share their Copilot conversations, we aim to:</p>
<ul dir="auto">
<li>Increase the visibility and utility of Copilot by enabling users to share their productive interactions.</li>
<li>Foster a collaborative environment where users can learn from each other’s experiences and insights.</li>
<li>Drive user adoption and growth by leveraging the viral potential of shared conversations, which can attract new users to GitHub.</li>
<li>Gather valuable feedback and data on how users interact with shared content, which will inform future iterations and improvements of the feature.</li>
</ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:53:37.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enable Cron Expression Support for Dependabot Scheduling [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1096</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1096"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:52:07.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Today, Dependabot’s <code class="notranslate">schedule.interval</code> supports only predefined intervals: daily, weekly, and monthly. Users need a more flexible way to schedule custom Dependabot update frequencies.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Introducing support for cron expressions in <code class="notranslate">schedule.interval</code> in the <code class="notranslate">dependabot.yml</code> file will provide a more generic and robust solution, enabling users to define custom schedules that meet their specific needs.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:51:08.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Private Registry Org-Level Configuration for Java & C# for CodeQL [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1095</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1095"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:48:07.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">A new organization-level configuration option for adding secrets to access private registries will improve coverage for buildless CodeQL scans for Java and C#. Developers will have more confidence in the accuracy of the scans, and false negatives will be further reduced. Organization administrators will be able to easily add these credentials for use across all their repositories at once, reducing time spent on configuration and setup for CodeQL.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">Coverage and confidence of CodeQL scans will increase with this feature, leading to even better security outcomes and increased peace-of-mind for security managers, with minimal overhead for configuration and management.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:47:50.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[EPSS Scores for Dependabot Alerts [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1094</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1094"/>
        <updated>2025-02-21T21:32:36.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">EPSS (Exploit Prediction Scoring System) is a data-driven framework that estimates the likelihood of a software vulnerability being exploited in the wild. It helps organizations prioritize patching efforts based on real-world risk.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With EPSS scores in Dependabot alerts, customers can expect a new way to prioritize their Dependabot updates based on likelihood of exploitation via EPSS score.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:44:10.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Code scanning: Status information at the organization level [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1093</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1093"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:41:38.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Security overview will include code scanning status information for all repositories within the organization.</p>
<p dir="auto">Users will see a color coded identification of "green," "yellow," or "red" next to each repository in the organization. These indicators represent the status of the code scanning tool's setup and performance. Customers can access the repository to enhance the tool's performance.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">The feature will streamline code scanning setup and adoption. When users enable code scanning across an organization at scale, they can identify repositories where a code scanning tool is underperforming or malfunctioning and take corrective measures.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:40:31.000Z</published>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Enterprise Governance: Custom repo properties for enterprise [GA]]]></title>
        <id>https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1092</id>
        <link href="https://github.com/github/roadmap/issues/1092"/>
        <updated>2025-01-23T18:38:21.000Z</updated>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<img src="https://avatars.githubusercontent.com/u/134638657?u=796627b7b5613a75768e410a1ef8cd04cea589d7&v=4" width="64" height="64" alt=""/><br/><h3 dir="auto">Value Prop</h3>
<p dir="auto">Enterprise repository properties allows for the management of custom repository properties across your entire enterprise, allowing teams to apply consistent metadata across all of their repos.</p>
<h3 dir="auto">Expected Outcome</h3>
<p dir="auto">With enterprise repository properties, enterprises have a way to share consistent properties across all of their organization without having to manually synchronize properties and deal with duplication. This gives administrators a common way to describe their repositories, empowering consistent application of rules and search parameters.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>glider-bot</name>
            <email>glider-bot@noreply.github.com</email>
            <uri>https://github.com/glider-bot</uri>
        </author>
        <published>2025-01-23T18:38:02.000Z</published>
    </entry>
</feed>